<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cmrnttrd</title>
    <link>https://cmrnttrd.tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content on cmrnttrd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cmrnttrd.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Pre-Bootstrap Prometheus Alerts</title>
      <link>https://cmrnttrd.tech/posts/preventing-pre-bootstrap-prometheus-alerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmrnttrd.tech/posts/preventing-pre-bootstrap-prometheus-alerts/</guid>
      <description>The up time series in Prometheus is incredibly useful for monitoring the availability of your targets at a high level. In its most basic form, alerting on the health of your targets looks like this:
alert: InstanceDown expr: up == 0 for: 5m labels: - severity: page annotations: - summary: &amp;quot;Instance {{$labels.instance}} down&amp;quot; - description: &amp;quot;{{$labels.instance}} of job {{$labels.job}} has been down for more than 5 minutes.&amp;quot;  This alert will fire after Prometheus has been unable to scrape a target for 5 minutes straight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning Azure Automation Webhooks via ARM Templates</title>
      <link>https://cmrnttrd.tech/posts/azure-automation-webhooks-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmrnttrd.tech/posts/azure-automation-webhooks-arm/</guid>
      <description>Coming from AWS CloudFormation, my experiences so far with Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates have been quite positive. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Infrastructure-as-Code offering includes several features that CloudFormation users would kill for, like resource and property iteration and a more extensive set of functions for working with arrays and objects.
However, last week I encountered an issue that had me scratching my head. I was trying to provision a webhook resource to trigger an Azure Automation runbook, which has the following structure according to the ARM template reference:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://cmrnttrd.tech/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmrnttrd.tech/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Software Engineer based in Sydney, Australia. I graduated in 2015 from Western Sydney University with a Bachelor of Computer Science and have since been working in the cloud infrastructure space.
I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in distributed systems and infrastructure automation (yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m a shameless Kubernetes fanboy). In between coding sessions, you can find me nerding out about football (NFL/NRL), music, and whatever else has grabbed my attention at that given moment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>